蝙蝠岛甲午年秋季拍卖现在开始
The Jiawu Year autumn auction of...
请诸位熄灯
Bat Island begins now. Lights off, please
请蝙蝠公子
Mr. Bat. Please...
蝙蝠岛甲午年秋季拍卖现在开始
The auction begins now.
第一宗买卖是第四号房
The first transaction is from room no. 4
客人的身份来自东瀛的和尚
The client is a monk from Japan.
你要买什么？
What would you like to buy?
我要买楚留香的人头
I want the head of Chu Liu-hsiang.
想不到从神水宫回到岸上
I never realized it'd take 3 more days...
还要三天的水上路程
from Holy Water Palace to the mainland.
今天的雾很大
The fog has been quite heavy today
这是什么地方？
What's this place?
我也不知道
I've no idea.
前面有一户人家，我们过去问问
A house over there. Let's check it out.
这里刚才好像有一个好大的宴会
Looks like there's a big banquet here.
人呢？
Where're the people?
少林袈裟，丐帮酒丐
These people from shaolin, Beggars'...
终南乌山，罗浮彩翼
Gang and Mount Zhongnan,
这些都是武林响铛铛的人物
are all famous in boxers' world.
怎么都会一起死在这里呢？
Why did they all die here?
这个人倒奇怪，身为头陀
This monk looks weird.
穿这么花花绿绿的衣裳
Why's he in such a colorful attire?!
断了一只手，又断了一只脚
One of his arm and leg were broken.
你看
Hey look
你们是谁？
Who are you?
不，你们先告诉我
No, first tell me who you are!
我是谁
Who am I?
你不知道你自己是谁？
Don't you know who you are?
记不起来了
I can't recall
我也不知道我是谁
I don't know who I am
我记不起来了
Frankly I can't remember
真奇怪，我到底是谁呢？
strange. Who the hell am I?
我为什么到这里来
Why did I come here?
对，我要到蝙蝠岛去
Right. I need to go to the Bat Island.
我是要到蝙蝠岛去的
I need to go to Bat Island.
蝙蝠岛，那是一个很神秘的地方
Bat Island is a mysterious place.
我以前听说过
I've heard of it before.
你呢？楚香师？你有没有听说过？
How about you, Chu Liu-hsiang? Heard of it?
蝙蝠岛？这个名字我以前好像听过
Bat Island! It does sound familiar
我们在四明山庄
At simin villa, didn't we...
不是看到一个穿花花绿绿的头陀吗
see a monk in colorful clothes?
是呀！
Right!
他不是已经死了吗？
Was he already dead?
请坐
Please have a seat.
大师，你不是已经死了吗？
Master, did you die already?
你为什么这样问？
Why do you ask me such a question?
因为我好像看见过你的尸体
Because I did see your dead body.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
你快告诉我我死在哪里？
Tell me where did I die?
谁杀我？
Who killed me?
这到底怎么回事？
What the hell is this?
如果你真的死过
If you were killed,
应该知道凶手是谁
you should have seen the killer.
事情是这样的
The fact is...
他有一个双生兄弟
he has a twin brother.
跟他长的一模一样
They look and dress the same.
也是穿同样的衣服
Both are handicapped too, but one...
只不过一个缺左边一个缺右边
on the left and other on the right.
江湖上称呼他们兄弟俩为天地双残
They're known as the Ruin Brothers.
最近他弟弟被人害死了
The younger one was recently killed.
他到处在找凶手
He is looking for the murderer.
他弟弟的确是死了
His younger brother was killed,
但是凶手不是我们
but we didn't kill him.
我为什么要信你？
Why would I trust you?
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是我，我也不要你相信
I don't seek your trust.
不过站在你对面的
But standing right in front of you...
就是名满天下的楚留香
is the world famous Chu Liu-hsiang.
楚留香？
Chu Liu-hsiang?
原来是香师在此
You're Master Hsiang!
幸会幸会
Nice to meet you.
兄台是...
You're...
在下李玉函，内子柳无名
I'm Li Yuhan, my wife Liu Wumin.
刚才的事只不过是一场误会
The whole thing was just a misunderstanding
相公，你看
Honey, look...
对不起，小弟有要事先走一步
Excuse me. I've to leave now.
你看
Look...
她是谁？
Who is she?
枯梅大师
Master Fumei
你不会看错吧
Did you get it wrong?
绝对不会
No, I didn't.
那我们租一条船跟去看看
Let's rent a boat to check it out.
不对啊
Strange... I heard
听说枯梅大师早已退出江湖
he withdrew from the boxers' world.
怎么又会出现呢
Why does he show up again?
看，那就是刚才枯梅大师坐的船
Look at the boat he just took.
船夫，快点撑我们过去
Get us over there quick.
怎么会全条船都烧了
Why was the boat all burnt up?
我们好像来得太迟了
Looks like we're late.
你有没有觉得这次遭遇很奇怪
Do you think what happened was strange?
四明山庄死了十二个人
12 people were killed at simin villa.
武功高强的白衣汉
The skillful boxer in white clothes...
却忘记了自己是什么人
couldn't recall his identity and...
还有那个神秘的红颜白发
the mysterious youngster in white hair!
更重要的是
Most important of all, Master Fumei...
枯梅大师下了山却突然失了踪
appeared and now suddenly vanishes!
江湖上一定发生了一件大事
Something must've happened in boxers' world.
我也是这么想
I share the same view.
救命啊
Help!
无名，你忍耐
Wumin, hold on.
好疼
It's very painful!
店小二，快拿白酒来
Waiter, get me some wine.
好
Okay.
李兄，原来是你啊，什么事？
It's you, Li. What's the matter?
没什么，只是内人患有速疾
My wife just isn't feeling good all of a sudden
经常发作，疼起来很厉害
It occurs frequently and causes much pain
所以我想拿点白酒给她送药
I want some wine to mix medicine for her
客官，白酒来了
sir, the wine is here.
谢谢
Thanks.
对不起两位
Excuse me...
客官，酒菜都齐了
The dinner and drinks are all served
奇怪，他们两个都住在这儿
strange. I mean, they both staying here!
管他呢，反正我们红衣
Who cares? I've touched the red clothes,
黑衣白衣都碰过了
black and white clothes.
再来两个穿绿衣服的又怎么样
2 more green clothes is no big deal.
来...喝一杯
Come on, try it.
慢
Hold it
你斟酒是不是用右手的
Do you pour wine with your right hand?
是啊，我一向都是用右手的
Yes, I do.
那我们刚才回来的时候
When we came back...
酒壶是像这样放的
the wine pot was placed like this.
可是你刚才斟酒的时候
But when you pour wine,
酒壶却这样放
the pot becomes in this position
那就是说
Then...
我们到外面去看的时候
After we left for a while,
有人动过这个酒壶
someone had moved the pot.
对了
Right.
别喝了
Don't drink it.
我已经喝了一点了
I've already had a sip
香师...
Master Hsiang.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你的武功也不错
Your skill is remarkable...
因为江湖上能接我十招的没有几个
as very few can resist 10 attacks from me
但是我很奇怪
But I feel strange.
你的发招好像不是杀我
You're not going to kill me,
而是想拖延时间
but just to keep me here.
你们现在是调虎离山想杀楚香师
Your real purpose is to kill Master Hsiang
你倒不笨想得出来
After all you're not stupid, huh
不过你现在回去已经太迟了
But it's too late to realize it.
怎么，你没有死？
What? You're still alive?
其实我早就发现酒壶调了方向
I knew the wine pot was wrongly placed
我喝酒的时候
When I drank,
已经把酒倒在这个地方
I had poured the wine here.
你为什么要杀他？
Why did you kill him?
他跟你们两个动手
He fought with you two.
我想他一定不是好人
I think he mustn't be a good man.
就是因为他不是好人
It's because of this,
所以我们才有很多话要问他
I've many questions to ask him.
什么事？
What?
有人要行刺楚香师
Someone wants to assassinate Master Hsiang.
所以我把他杀了
So I've killed him.
什么？居然有人要杀楚香师
What? How would he dare to kill Hsiang?
那人一定是疯了
He must be crazy.
李兄，这宝剑
Li, is this precious sword...
是不是上古失传的苍山古诀
the ancient, long-Iost Cangshan sword?
这宝剑失传已久
This sword was lost for years.
怎么会落到李兄的手里
How did you get it?
香师有听说过雍翠山庄没有？
Have you heard of the Jade villa?
我当然听说过
Yes, of course.
雍翠山庄乃天下第一剑客李关瑜
Jade villa is where the no. 1 swordsman...
收藏稀世宝剑之所
Li Guanyu keeps his precious swords.
李关瑜正是家父
Li Guanyu is my father.
如果两位相公有兴趣的话
If you're interested,
可以驾临寒舍
please come and visit my place.
还有很多稀世的宝剑呢
We've collected many precious swords.
欣赏名剑正是我楚留香
Appreciating precious swords...
生平嗜好之一
always gives me immense pleasure.
一点红，你有没有兴趣？
Yi Tien-hung, will you join me?
我半生对剑已经有点腻了
I'm tired of dealing with swords.
而且我有点事情要办
Besides, I've things to do
还是各位请吧
Please excuse me.
从这里开始
From here,
已经是我们雍翠山庄的地界了
it's already the domain of Jade villa
好漂亮
Brilliant
香师如果有兴趣的话
If it interests you,
请四处浏览一下
you may take a look wherever you please
我们先回去预备为香师洗尘
We'd have to leave to arrange for the meals
好...
okay...
前面的房子就是寒舍
over there is our home
请
Please...
楚香师，您来了
Master Hsiang, here you are
这个地方好漂亮
This place is beautiful.
这就是先父试剑的地方
This is where my father tested the swords.
李老前辈爱剑如此
Mr. Li was really a swords lover.
真不愧天下第一剑客
He deserved being the no. 1 swordsman.
先父以剑成名也视剑如命
My father valued the swords a great deal.
只要与剑有关的事他都有兴趣
He took interest in everything related to swords
可惜他在临终之前
But before he died,
还有一个未了的心愿
he had an unfulfilled wish.
什么心愿？
What's the wish?
因为先父研究遍了
My father studied...
古往今来所有的剑法
every kind of sword fight
始终想不出一个战无不胜的剑阵
He had not invented an invincible sword troop.
为了爱剑，他穷一生精力
He devoted his life for swords...
创出一套五行剑阵
and invented Wuhan sword array.
可惜一直无法证明
But still it hasn't been proved...
是否真正天下无敌
if it's invincible.
为什么？
How come?
因为找不到一个破阵的人
Because no one tried this sword formation
这人不但要有绝顶的武功
The person must be the best fighter.
而且要有绝顶的名气
Also he has to be quite reknown
只有这样胜败才可以响遍江湖
Then the result will become outstanding
目下江湖上有此条件的
Master Hsiang is the only qualified boxer...
只有香师一人
in the world.
所以贤伉俪才千方百计的
So you and your wife tried your best...
引我到这里来
to ensure bringing me here
这是你的剑
This is your sword.
我今天好像没有选择的余地
Seems like I don't have a choice today
请指教，上
Please...
看起来李老前辈的心愿
I think Mr. Li's wish wasn't to do a test...
不是想试剑阵，而是想要杀我
but to kill me.
此话怎讲？
Why do you say so?
因为这个剑阵如果没有破绽
If there's no defeat in the sword troop,
我会马上死在这里
I'd die here immediately
就算有破绽
Even if there's a defeat,
凭这五个高手联手攻我
with 5 skillful swordsmen attacking me,
我也会死在这里
I'll be surely dead.
在六福客栈的时候
At the Liufu Inn,
我已经感到很奇怪
it already felt strange, as to...
你为什么要杀那黑衣人灭口
why'd someone kill the man in black!
李玉函，我到底与你有什么仇恨？
Li Yuhan, what's wrong?
别多问了
Don't ask anymore.
反正我们引你来就是真的想杀你
We just want to kill you.
李老前辈的五行剑阵确很厉害
Your father's sword troop is really good
现在看起来这个剑阵
Looks like Chu Liu-hsiang can't...
连楚香师都破不了
defeat the sword troop.
别动
Don't move.
在下十五年前早已仰慕
For 15 years I've been admiring the...
老前辈的出手双绝鸳鸯神剑
greatness of your Yuanyang swords.
今天能够亲身领教不胜荣幸
My pleasure fighting against you today.
你怎么认出来的？
How did you recognize me?
用惯双剑的人突然改用单剑
When playing with 2 swords, a person uses: : :
另一只手一定紧握拳头
Only one; the other hand always forms a fist.
而惯用单剑的人
For someone using just a single sword,
另一只手一定是捏着剑诀
the fingers of his other hand are usually out.
我就利用老前辈的这个习惯
This is your habit I'm employing, sir...
突然把剑交给你
Handing you a sword all of a sudden
相信你们大家也明白
I think you will understand.
这剑阵少不了一把剑
This sword array can't have one sword less...
当然也多不了剑一把
and of course can't have one more.
楚留香不愧为楚留香
Chu Liu-hsiang is really good.
铁山道长，君子剑，竹剑削石
Priest Tieshan, Gentlemen sword and
你们每一位
Bamboo sword, all of you...
都是名门正派的顶尖高手
are top swordsmen from righteous schools
难怪你们都要蒙面了
No wonder you all cover face with a mask
我楚留香到底什么地方得罪了前辈
What actually have I done to offend you?
你们非要置我于死地不可
Why did you have to kill me?
我们绝非要杀香师
We didn't intend to kill you,
只为报恩而来
but to pay our debts. Li's family...
李家三代单传
has only one son for 3 generations
现在嫂夫人梦熊有兆
Mrs. Li was pregnant,
不幸身染怪病
but she has a special disease, which can...
要用天竺罂粟才能止痛安胎
only be cured by the poppy from India
而这卖药的人要香师的头去换
But the poppy seller asked for your life
为救故人一点血脉，所以...
save the only son of an old friend...
住手...
Hold it.
世兄，楚香师既破剑阵于前
Li, Master Hsiang defeated the formation...
又不下杀手于后
and didn't try to kill us.
你现在反而恩将仇报
Now you repay his goodness.
李家子弟怎能做此不仁不义之事
We can't do these kind of immoral things.
不孝有三，无后为大
Lacking filial devotion is a great sin.
我李玉函也顾不了这么多了
You see, I can't afford caring too much.
各位前辈，你们挡着我的剑干什么
Why are you blocking me, sir?
铁山道长
Priest Tieshan, can you bear...
你能眼看我李家无后吗？
watching Li's family terminated?
如果我这手一放，江湖道义何存？
Where's the justice if I let you go?
我以后又怎能再去管武当几千子弟
Hereafter how can I face my Wutang students?
但是我父亲救命之恩你不能不报
But you can't refuse to pay my father's debt
好吧
okay.
道长...
Priest...
楚留香
Chu Liu-hsiang
你亲眼看到我臂膀已断不能救你
I'm not able to save with my broken arm.
有铁山道长这样的人
Owing to such a person like Priest Tieshan,
可见江湖道义这四个字也全非骗人
the word 'justice' still lives on
你还等什么？
What are you waiting for?
前辈大恩，没齿不忘
Thank you, sir.
无名...你干什么
Wumin, what are you doing?
玉函，算了吧
Yuhan, forget it.
还是铁山道长说的对
What Priest Tieshan said is right.
李家子弟不能做此不仁不义的事
The Li family can't do wrong things.
可是，你的病呢
But your illness...
我是江湖上一个无名之辈
I'm a nobody in the boxers' world.
又怎能拿香师的性命来比
Nothing to compare with hsiang's life.
香灯之事，等我死了你再另娶吧
After my death, I request you to re-marry
香师你原谅他吧
Please forgive him, master hsiang.
他这样做无非是为了我
What he did was because of me.
至于我们夫妇欠你的
What we owed you,
等我死了来生再还吧
we'd pay you back in next life.
大嫂，我的命是你救回来的
You saved my life.
我楚留香怎么能
How can I...
让救命恩人白白的死去呢
let you die for nothing?
告诉我
Tell me...
你的天竺罂粟在哪里可以买得到
where can I buy the poppy from India?
蝙蝠岛
Bat Island.
蝙蝠岛是近年来的一个
Bat Island is a recent...
黑帮帮会的组织
uprising triad organisation
听说里面只要有钱
It's known that if you've money,
就什么毒品，人命
you can buy drugs, life or...
武林的秘密都有得买的
even the secrets of the boxers' world.
谁是主人？
Who heads that gang?
有一个叫蝙蝠公子的
Someone called Mr. Bat.
他武功极高
He's an extremely good fighter.
但是没有人知道他是谁
But no one knows who he is
为什么呢？
Why?
因为他们做买卖的时候不许点灯
When they conduct a deal, no lights are on.
所以一直没有人见过
So, no one ever sees...
他的庐山真面目
his real face.
有什么方法可以去蝙蝠岛吗
How can I go to the Bat Island?
那我就不知道了
I don't know.
为什么没有人问我们呢？
Why doesn't anyone ever ask us?
怎么？我不是人吗？
What? Aren't we people?
你又没问我们
You didn't ask us.
我的宋姑娘，李姑娘
My dearest Miss song and Miss Li,
我楚留香
I, Chu Liu-hsiang,
有什么方法可以去蝙蝠岛啊
ask you how I can reach the island.
最近皇后失了一条珍珠腰带
The Queen lost a pearl waist-belt lately
听说给隐身大盗朱同偷去了
The Invisible Thief Zhu Tong has stolen it
偷了皇帝的无价之宝只有一个方法
He can sell the things stolen from...
就是到蝙蝠岛去把它卖掉
the King at Bat Island.
如果我要到蝙蝠岛
Say, If I had to go to Bat Island,
就先要找到那个隐身大盗
I'd rather find the Invisible Thief first.
对
Right.
不过听说到蝙蝠岛的人都要有记号
I know whoever goes there needs a mark.
这个李玉函倒给了我
Li Yuhan has given me the mark.
不过不知道要用什么方法
But I don't know how...
可以跟蝙蝠岛的人取得联络呢
I can get in touch with the people there.
我知道偷了珍珠腰带的人
I know the one who stole the belt...
已经到了秦淮河
has arrived at the Qinhuai River.
他是怎么样的人
What kind of a person is he?
那还不简单，一定生成像个贼一样
Simple. He must look like a thief.
客官里边请...
Please come in...
客官请坐
Please be seated
那个隐身大盗
The Invisible Thief...
还不是长得像个贼一样
does indeed look like a thief!
快点
Come on.
兄弟，我不是坏人
Brother, I'm not a bad guy.
我只不过想问你几句话
I just want to ask you a few questions.
哑仆，还不快点进来
Mute buddy, come in quick.
奇怪
Strange... why does this house...
这房子为什么会漂到大海中央呢？
float to the middle of the sea?
在这里为什么会有一所大房子呢
Why is there a big house here?
这房子怎么会动呢
How can it move?
为什么我的房子也向着大屋走呢
Why does my house move towards it?
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
这个你不必知道
You don't need to know.
我又不认识你
I don't know you.
你为什么要杀我
Why did you try to kill me?
就是因为我不认识你
I don't know you.
所以才要杀你
That's the reason I have to kill you.
你杀我之前能不能告诉我
Before you kill me, can you tell me why...
这小房子为什么会走进这大屋里
this small house is drawn toward the big one?
因为我们在这个房子底下
Because under the house,
有条很长的绳子在拉它
there's a long rope pulling it.
难怪
I see.
这大海里的房子谁是主人啊？
Who's the master of the big house?
蝙蝠岛的蝙蝠公子
Mr. Bat of Bat Island.
原来他们是从这里到蝙蝠岛的
So they go to Bat Island from here.
你管不着
None of your business.
你还没有告诉我你是谁
You've not told me who you are
等一会万一你真的杀了我
In case you kill me later, I can at least tell...
罗王问我谁送你下去的
the Hell Master who sent me there.
我答不上来怎么办？
You know, it'll be so embarrassing if I can't
你倒很风趣，我叫向飞天
You're a funny man. I'm Xiang Feitian,
是蝙蝠岛七十八分舵的管事
keeper of the 78th branch of the Island
每个人由这里到蝙蝠岛
Everyone going to the Island...
都是由我负责的
will be taken care of by me.
负责什么？
Take care of what?
如果是客人，负责送他去
If you're a guest, I'll escort you through
不是客人，负责杀了他
If not, I'll kill you.
你怎么知道我不是客人
How do you know I'm not a guest?
因为我从未见过你
Because I haven't seen you before.
可是我家主人你却见过
But you did meet my master.
他是谁？
Who might he be?
雍翠山庄的李玉函
Li Yuhan of Jade villa.
李玉函登记的是哪一号？
In which category is he registered?
宇字号
Yu category.
他要买什么？            天竺罂粟
- What does he want to buy? - Poppy.
字据呢？
Proof?
那你真的是我们的客人了
You are our guest.
第三站的客人到
Guests from the 3rd stop have arrived
第三站你登记哪一号？
Which category you registered at 3rd stop?
地字号
Di category.
公孙洁明
Gongsun Jiemin...
在下正是
Yes, it's me
第五站客人到
Guests from 5th stop arrived.
第五站龙公子登记是玄字号
Mr. Long registered with Xuan.
字据在这里
Here's the proof
龙五公子，怎么？
Mr. Long Wu, what's the matter?
你带了两个随从来
You brought along 2 servants.
是的，我由出娘胎开始到现在
Yes. They've been taking care of me...
一直都有两个人服侍我
since my birth
不过，船费很贵喔
But the boat fee is very expensive.
金子在这里
The money is here.
好了，我们开始下去吧
Okay, let's go.
请
Please...
诸位，请            请...
- Please - Please...
你想干什么？
What do you want?
我想扶你
I'm trying to help you.
谢谢...
Thanks.
诸位请
Please...
请...
请
Please...
请船主
Boatsman, please.
人都到齐啦
Everyone is here.
都到齐了
All are here.
你先带他们下去
Take them inside first.
把房间给他们分配好
Let them check in their rooms.
请...
Please...
请
这边
This way.
请
Lady, please.
姑娘，请
Please...
一点红
Yi Tien-hung.
你又怎么会上了这条船的呢
Why are you here?
因为我接了一单生意
I'm on business.
要去杀一个人
I've someone to kill.
我们分开以后，我就接了一封信
After you had gone, I got a letter...
说给我一百万两黄金
saying I'd get 1 million taels of gold...
去杀一个人
to kill someone.
于是我就依着地址去见一个人
So I followed the address to meet a man.
那个人又带我上了这条船
The man brought me here and told me that...
他说我要杀的人在蝙蝠岛
the man I need to kill is on the Island
什么，到蝙蝠岛去杀人，杀谁？
What? Kill someone on the Island? Who?
不知道，我只知道
No idea. What I do know is just that...
他身上有一件很特别的东西
the man has a very special thing.
根据飞鸽传书
According to the pigeon's note,
二十四个分舵的船已经开出
boats from the 24 branches were gone.
这一次到蝙蝠岛的客人共有362位
The guests going to Bat Island this time
这么说我们船上的人
Guests on our boat...
已经全部调查过了
were all checked.
全部调查过了
All were checked.
天字号的人是一个孝女
There's a filial lady in Tian room.
她到蝙蝠岛的原因
She's on her way to the Island...
是去买回她的父亲
because she wants to buy her father back
她说她的父亲被囚在蝙蝠岛
she said he was confined on the island.
那个哑巴是她的忠仆
The dumb man is her loyal servant,
永远跟在她的身边
staying by her side forever.
地字号的人
The guest at Di room...
是一个有钱的武林人物
is a wealthy boxer.
他到蝙蝠岛的目的
He goes to the Island...
只想买一点奇珍异宝
to buy something precious.
至于玄字号的人
The guest at Xuan room...
表面上看起来是一个富家子弟
Iooks like a man from a wealthy family.
其实我们查到他是御前侍卫
But I know he's a royal guard.
他可能是去调查
Maybe he's investigating...
皇后失去的珍珠腰带的事
the case of the Queen's lost pearl.
黄字号的人呢
The guest at Wang room;
这个人就比较神秘了
um... he's kind of mysterious!
他什么都不说
He didn't say a word.
只给了我十颗明珠
He just gave me 10 pearls and asked...
他只说想到蝙蝠岛躲几年
to hide on the Island for a few years
看起来他倒像是
Looks like he could be the one...
偷去皇后珍珠腰带的人
who stole the Queen's pearl.
报告船主，总舵的飞鸽传书飞到了
A letter from headquarters is here.
这不对
This isn't right.
总舵说我们的船上有奸细
The letter says there's a spy on the boat
公子还吩咐我们带尸体回去
Mr. Bat asked us to bring his body back
六副够了
6 will be enough.
照我们以前的办法
The same old way...
把总舵要杀的人一个一个的杀掉
Kill everyone the headquarter wants.
明天开始动手
Do it tomorrow.
谁啊？
Who?
我啊
It's me.
你...
You...
你鬼鬼祟祟的找我们干什么
Why are you looking for me stealthily?
你们跟我来
Follow me.
昨天晚上
Yesterday night...
我就是看到他们在这里说的
I heard they said...
要把我们一个个的杀掉
they'd kill all of us.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我叫金灵芝
I'm Jin Linzhi.
我爹一生研究盖房子
My dad specializes in building houses.
五年前，有一个人请我爹去造房子
5 years ago, my dad was given a contract
以后他就没有回来
After that, he didn't came back.
最近我才查出他被困在蝙蝠岛
I found out he's captured at the Island
所以我千方百计的带同我家哑仆
so I'm going along with my servant...
到蝙蝠岛去
to the bat island.
我要救我爹
I have to save my dad
香师我一定要到蝙蝠岛去
Master Hsiang, I must go to the Island.
我不能在半路上被他们杀了
I can't let them kill me.
轻一点...金姑娘
Quiet... Miss Jin.
第一你不知道他们要杀谁
First, you don't know who they will kill
第二你不知道他们
second, you don't know when...
什么时候下手
they will do it.
我知道，他们说今天早上就下手
I know. They said this morning.
说不定已经有人死了
Maybe someone has been killed already
想不到他倒先死了
I never thought he'd be killed first.
原来躲在门外偷听的
The one hiding behind the door
是我们船上的总管
is the keeper of this boat.
因为我想知道谁那么爱管闲事
I want to know who's the officious one.
船主是我今天早上
This morning I found the boatsman...
发现他死在床上的
lying dead on the bed.
他的心脉昨天晚上给震断了
Someone broke his artery last night.
你们船主武功那么高
Even though he was a good boxer...
也会给人杀死
he's killed by someone.
当然会
Why not?
不然的话他怎么会死呢
Or else why did he die?
而且我敢说这条船上还会有人
I think there'll be more people here...
来人啊...
Help...
是谁杀死他们的？
Who killed them?
我不知道
I don't know.
刚才我送饭菜的时候
When I brought them meals,
他们三个已经躺在地下
they're already dead on the ground.
而他们两位已经站在那里了
And 2 of them are standing there.
我们是听到了打斗的声音
We heard the sound of fighting...
才走过来的
and came over.
那你们有没有看到谁走过去
Did you see anyone going there?
没有
No.
你为什么要杀我？
Why do you want to kill me?
我要灭口，因为只有你一个人知道
To keep your mouth shut as you're the...
我杀了御前侍卫
only one who knows I killed the guard.
你错了
You're wrong.
今天早上我进去
When I came in this morning...
见到你一个人站着的时候
and saw you standing there,
我只是怀疑
I just suspected.
到现在我才知道你是真正的凶手
Not until now did I realize you're the killer.
干什么？
What's the matter?
他想杀我
He wants to kill me.
为什么？
Why?
你问他好了
You'd better ask him.
什么事啊？
What's going on?
他杀了人
He killed someone.
奇怪
Strange.
我们都是刚从船舱下面上来的
We just came up here from the cabin.
是谁杀死他的？
Who killed him?
老先生，事到如今
Sir, are you still...
你还想杀他灭口
going to kill to keep the secret?
我为什么要灭口？
Why do you want to keep the secret?
你怕他抓你
You're afraid he'd arrest you.
因为今天死的是
Since the one who was killed...
当今皇上御前侍卫
is a royal guard,
而你就是那个闻名江湖的隐身大盗
and you're the well-known Invisible Thief...
而偷了皇后珠链的也就是你
who stole the Queen's pearl.
怎么？又死了一个？
What? One more person has been killed?
这条船上还有一个人他在哪里？
Ought to be 1 more person here. But where?
还有一个人？谁？
One more people? Who?
就是刚才杀死那个穿白衣服的
The one who has killed the one in white...
跟现在杀死那个老头的人
and kills the old man now.
而且那个人的武功很高
Besides that person is a very good boxer.
他在哪儿？
Where's he?
你们看
Look...
我早就说过他的武功很高
I know he's a very good boxer.
只有他杀人，没有人能随便杀他
He killed. No one could resist him.
什么？那个船主没有死
What? The boat owner wasn't dead yet.
不但没有死
Not only that, but...
刚才那两个人都是他杀的
the two men were killed by him.
不错
Right.
因为只有这样才能使你们没有预防
By doing so, you'd overlook him...
只有这样才是最好的杀人方法
and it'd be the best way to kill.
为什么要杀我们？
Why did he try to kill us?
我们总舵发觉了这船上有奸细
Headquarter mentioned there're spies on the boat
因为当今皇上
Because the King has ordered...
派出了武功盖世的御前高手
the best royal guard to
想抓我们的蝙蝠公子
arrest Mr. Bat.
再加上爱多管闲事的楚香师
The officious Master Hsiang...
也在我们的船上
is also on the boat.
所以船主就干脆把船上的人
So the owner planned to kill...
全部杀死
all people on the boat.
你们船主现在在哪里？
Where's the boat owner now?
既然给你们发觉了
As you guys found out the fact, he'd
所以他坐另外一条船先回岛去
gone back to the Island on another boat.
放屁
Bullshit.
向飞天，你错了
Xiang Feitian, you're wrong.
你怎么可以杀死我们
How could you kill us all?
我们蝙蝠公子做事
Mr. Bat never...
从来没有做错那回事
does things in a wrong way.
你们有没有看见那个蜡烛？
Don't you see the candle?
蜡烛怎么样？
What's wrong with it?
到蜡烛点完的时候
When it's gone,
船马上就会爆炸
the boat will be blown off...
而你们就会死在海上
and you'll be dead in the sea.
坏了
Holy...!
炸药一定在蜡烛台的下面
The dynamite must be under the candle.
快，快点进去帮一下忙
Hurry up. Go inside and help.
快，快进去
Go inside quick.
快点...
Hurry up.
真没想到，坐在棺材里在海上漂浮
I never thought sitting and floating in...
比坐在船上还写意得多了
a coffin would be more relaxing than on a boat
一点红大侠，我们现在在海中央
Yi Tien-hung, we're in the middle of the sea
四边都看不到岸，怎么办啊？
The shore is out of sight. What'd we do?
他们不是给你预备好了棺材了吗？
Did they prepare the coffin for you?
晚上的海风真凉快啊
The night sea breeze is really cool.
你们看前面有条船
There is a boat over there
奇怪，怎么会有人在海上漂浮呢？
Why are the people drifting in the sea?
启禀公子，有五个人坐在棺材上
Sir, there're many people drifting...
在海面漂浮
in coffins.
那么马上去把他们救起来
Then save them immediately.
快放绳梯...
Put the rope down.
请...
Please...
请
Please
嘉客远临，未能亲迎，恕罪恕罪
Please forgive my ignorance.
哪里哪里，劫后余生承蒙搭救
Not at all. Thanks for saving us.
已是喜出望外，若主人还如此客气
We'll feel embarrassed...
在下等实在不知如何是好
if you still blame yourself.
哪里哪里，能为众英雄略尽绵薄
It's my honor...
亦属天幸
to be of little help to you.
众英雄又何必多礼
Please make yourself comfortable.
禀公子，酒菜准备好了
Sir, the meal is served
各位请坐请坐...
Please be seated
少主人幼年患疾双目失明
Young master became blind when he was small
若有礼曼之处，还望众英雄见谅
Do forgive us for any mistake due to oversight
诸位，现在耳中无琴眼前有酒
Ladies and gentlemen, I'd like to...
来，我先敬各位一杯
drink first to show my respects
请...
Please...
久闻楚香师乃酒中之豪
I know Master Hsiang is a wine conossieur
不晓得这家藏旧酿能否入口
Is the wine good enough for you?
你怎么知道他是楚留香？
How do you know he's Chu Liu-hsiang?
方才人报五人上船
I was informed of 5 people getting off the boat.
但在下只闻四人足声
But I only heard footsteps of four
当今之士能落地无声
In the boxers' world, only Master Hsiang...
除香师之外还能有谁？
can land without making a sound.
杀人不费吹灰力
To kill with ease...
一点红大侠
Yi Tien-hung
在下敬你一杯
I raise a toast to you.
你又怎么知道他是一点红呢？
How do you know he's Yi Tien-hung?
当世双雄大破神水宫
The 2 heroes busting the Holy Water Palace
天下有谁不晓？
Can anyone not be shocked by it?
能与香师平排起坐的
To walk and sit side by side with Hsiang
除大侠外还有谁人？
It must be the Hero Yi Tien-hung.
请
Please
公子虽然目力不佳
Though your eye-sight isn't very good,
但比起我们看得见的人还要强的多
you do see much better than many of us.
哪里哪里，另外几位是...
Thanks. The others are...
我叫金灵芝        在下是勾子长
- I'm Jin Linzhi. - I'm Gou Zicheng.
勾壮士，金姑娘，请
Mr. Gou and Miss Jin, please...
请
Please...
对了，几位为什么会在海上漂浮？
Why did you drift in the sea?
说来话长
A long story...
反正我们坐的船出了意外
our boat had an accident.
对了，坐了半天
Right. I'd have asked...
还未问阁下尊姓大名呢？
how I should address you.
敝姓V草字随云
I'm Yuan suiyun.
这个姓倒很少
Your surname isn't a common one.
却不知贵乡何处？
Where's your hometown?
关中人
I come from Guanzhong.
关中V氏，在江湖中的声望很浓
It's a famous boxer's family.
无争山庄更是武林的第一大庄
Wuzheng villa is also the biggest villa.
却不知阁下与V老庄主
I wonder if Master Yuan...
是什么关系？
is from your family?
正是先父
He's my father.
无争山庄的V老庄主不但家财万贯
He's not only a very rich man, but also...
在江湖中的地位极高
a reputed man in the boxers' world.
他家山庄用无争这两个字
The title of his villa was given...
是天下武林豪杰送给他的
by other famous boxers
意思就是江湖中
It meant among the boxers,
已经无人可以与他争一日之长短了
no one can compare to him.
他的武功真的那么厉害？
Is he really skillful at fighting?
不过，三年之前他已经死了
But he passed away 3 years ago.
对了，听说这个少庄主
I heard this young master...
自小就有神童之称
has been a genius since he's a child.
文武双全才高八斗
He's good at fighting and also at academics
而且品性十分敦厚
And he's of a generous character.
江湖传说
The boxers' world said...
华山派的枯梅大师遁世逃情
Master Fumei of Huashan school is a hermit
就是为了这无争山庄的V老英雄
But she and Mr. Yuan of Wuzheng villa...
而且，还跟他生了两个儿子
had two sons.
不错，枯梅大师
Right. Master Fumei...
跟V老英雄生了两个儿子
and Mr. Yuan are proud parents of 2 boys.
大的枯梅自己带走
Fumei took away the elder son.
只留下小的在V家
The younger one was left to Yuan.
他们为什么会闹翻的？
What's the trouble between them?
女人很多时候都无理取闹的
Women are always unreasonable.
进来
Come in
我们公子请诸位到甲板上
My lord invites you to partake refreshments...
用点点心
on the deck.
谢谢
Thanks.
请
Please...
送饭菜的
The meal is here.
谢谢
Thanks
枯梅大师
Master Fumei...
奇怪，他们不是
strange. Didn't they...
在秦淮河外沉船死了的吗？
drown at the Qinhuai River?
怎么会在这里？
How come they are here?
这条船在这里本来就有点奇怪
As such this already is a strange boat
我们先去吃饭吧
Let's have the meals first.
我服侍的客人真麻烦
The guests I serve give me trouble.
一天要吃几顿
They've several meals a day.
我的也是，整天要吃止疼药
Mine too. She takes medicine very often.
听说这些罂粟药很贵
I know the poppy is very expensive.
是从天竺买的呢
It's only from India.
是啊
Yes.
客官，你的药
Here's your medicine.
谢谢
Thanks.
快点去吃饭了
Let's have the meal first.
吃饭吃饭
Come on.
那不是四明山庄
Was he the man in white who...
患了失忆症的白衣人吗？
Iost his memory at the simin villa?
奇怪，他怎么会在船上？
Strange. Why is he here?
别动，不要出声
Don't move and make no sound.
原来是你，刚才的事你看见了？
It's you. Did you see that?
还有，跟我来
Follow me.
李玉函夫妇，枯梅大师，白衣人
Mr. And Mrs. Li, Master Fumei,
还有那个丁峰
the Man in White and Dingfeng.
他们在这条船上干什么？
What are they doing on the boat?
你有没有想过
Didn't you think...
他们也是坐这条船到蝙蝠岛去
they're going to Bat Island on this boat?
你说这条船要到蝙蝠岛去
Is this boat going to Bat Island?
怎么会呢？
How can it?
无争山庄的人是江湖上最有体面的
Wucheng villa is a reputed family.
他们到蝙蝠岛去干什么呢？
What are they doing at Bat Island?
譬如说V家大少爷
The young master Yuan...
给那白发红袍威胁
was threatened by the one in white hair
那么这条船不到蝙蝠岛也不成
The boat will go to Bat Island definitely
不会，这条船的航线是到金鲤岛的
The boat is heading towards Carp Island.
奇怪，你到底是谁？
Strange. Who the hell are you?
你对天下间的事情
Why do you know each & every detail...
为什么调查得这么清楚？
of everything?
我是我，是一个要到蝙蝠岛去的人
I'm me, a person heading for Bat Island.
看样子我们到最后
Look like, at last...
还是要到蝙蝠岛去
we'll be going to Bat Island
因为不到那里
since we can only find the answers
有很多事情不会弄清楚
for our questions there.
不过，这条船还是先会去金鲤岛的
But this boat will go to Carp Island first
禀公子，这里已经发现了金鲤鱼
sir, we find the golden carps here.
那么马上下网打捞
Then get it up now.
是
Yes.
这种鲤鱼只在这金鲤岛才有
It can be only found near Carp Island.
味道非常鲜美
It tastes very good.
我就是为了它才把船驶到这里来
That's the reason I've brought my boat here
鱼来了
The fish is coming.
快...
Hurry up.
怎么是人？
How come it's a man?
禀公子，他们网上了四个
Sir, we fished...
一丝不挂的裸女
4 naked women.
是活的还是死的？
Dead or alive?
她们呼吸都没有了
They don't have any breath,
但心还在跳
but their hearts are still beating.
那可能是刚刚晕倒的
Maybe they've just passed out
你们马上把她们送到天号房
Get them to Tian room now.
兰太夫人那里去
Ask Mrs. Nan to go there.
是
Yes
奇怪，她们从哪里来？
Where do they come from?
又怎么会钻到渔网里去的呢？
How could they get into the net?
快点快点，抬进屋里去
Hurry up. Get them into the room.
禀夫人，这几个女子的心脉停了
Madam, their heartbeats have stopped.
我们公子请你马上救她们
Sir asked you to save them immediately.
出去        出去...快出去
Get out... immediately.
她们到底怎么搞的？
What the hell are they doing?
师父...
Master...
公子公子不得了
sir, big trouble!
刚才那四个女子把兰太夫人杀死了
The 4 girls killed madam.
什么？
What?
摘心手
The Heart Pluck Hand!
不错，是我师父临死前杀死她们的
True, Master killed them before she died.
这几个女的是什么人？
Who are these girls?
我不知道
I don't know.
香师，你呢？
Master Hsiang, do you know?
我也不知道
I don't know.
她们派凶手来行刺枯梅大师
Someone ordered them to kill the master
武功一定很高
The one must be a very good fighter,
而且，主使他们的人势力一定很大
and a powerful man.
蝙蝠岛的人？
From Bat Island?
我们马上开船回去
We're heading there right now.
今天晚上我们绝对不能睡觉
We must not go to bed tonight.
要解六道穴道
I need to unlock 6 body points.
不要动，我是来救你的
Don't move. I'm here to save you.
谁叫你救我的？
Who asked you to come?
你娘，枯梅大师
Your mother, Master Fumei.
你怎么晓得我是枯梅大师的私生子
How do you know I'm his son?
我的他的徒弟高雅南
I happen to be her student Gao Yanan.
那边有小船，跟我来
Follow me to the small boat over there.
香师香师，不好了
Master Hsiang, something is wrong.
我们的船停了
Our boat has stopped.
走
Run.
船已经在山洞里面
The boat is in a cave.
快上去看看
Hurry. Go up and look
不用看了，我上去过
No need. I've been there.
上面一个人也没有
No one is there.
不用下去了
No need to go down.
下面一个人也没有
No one's down there.
李玉函夫妇不在
Mr. And Mrs. Li aren't there.
屋内一个人也没有
No one's in the house.
枯梅大师的尸首也不见了
The body of Master Fumei is also gone.
那V公子呢？
Where's Mr. Yuan?
不要打，自己人
Stop. It's a friend.
李公子，我们正在找你
Mr. Li, we're looking for you.
你怎么会在这里的
Why are you here?
是无争山庄的V少庄主
Mr. Yuan of Wuchang villa...
请我们去金鲤岛去赏金鲤的
invited us to the Carp Island.
想不到她一上船就病到现在
But she felt sick once boarding the boat
所以我们一直没有离开过船舱
We didn't leave the cabin at all.
你不知道我们在船上吗？
You didn't know we're on the boat.
我们只知道有很多朋友上船来
I knew many friends boarding the boat,
却不知道是你们
but I didn't know it's you.
那V少庄主在哪里啊？
Where is Mr. Yuan?
我也不知道
Have no idea
当我发觉船停了走过来
When I noticed that the boat has stopped,
他已经不在了
he wasn't there anymore.
会不会那穿红衣服的把他押走了？
Did the one in red take him away?
这迷药好厉害
The drug is really strong.
居然连我这坏鼻子的人也迷倒了
Even I with a stuffy nose have passed out.
这是什么地方啊？
What is this place?
我们一醒过来
When we woke up,
就已经被吊在这里了
we're already hung here.
有一种九黝生铁
There's a Black Iron
是世上最坚硬的东西
which is the hardest thing in the world
就算你们的武功再高
No matter how powerful you are,
也休想动它分毫
you can't break it.
你们看
Look...
看起来这山谷
Look at this valley
只有那一道门可以走出去
there's only a single door out.
我们先想想怎么样才能逃出这铁笼
Let's think of a way out of this cage.
我们雍翠山庄有一把盘古金剑
We've a Gold sword at Jade villa.
削铁如泥
It can break iron like paper.
不知道能不能砍断这九黝生铁
I wonder if it could break this Black Iron too
现在我们可以跳到水里游过去
We now get into the water and swim there
慢
Hold it.
蝙蝠公子绝不会只用一个
Mr. Bat won't use only a...
九黝生铁的铁笼
cage made of Black Iron
来困住名闻天下的楚香师
to trap the reputed Master Hsiang
跟一点红大侠
and Yi Tien-hung.
我小时候听说过一种硝水
I know of a certain kind of acid...
能把所有的东西都溶掉
that can melt anything.
我想这恐怕就是硝水池了
I'm afraid this is an acid pool.
果然是硝水池
Yes, it's an acid pool.
那我们怎么可以到那洞口呢？
How can I get to the exit?
那山边又是火
There's a fire over there.
就算我们能攀山过去
We can climb over there,
金小姐绝不可能的
but Miss Jin mightn't be able to do it.
看起来现在只有一个方法
There's only one way out.
就是像食物一样一个一个的吊过去
It'll be like hanging food one by one.
这铁丝只能吊食物
Only food could be hung on the wire!
人那么重怎么成呢？
Would the wire bear the weight of people?
我这里有一条七彩天蚕丝
I've here the Magic silk Wire,
是世上最坚韧的宝物
the most pliable but strongest material
我把它绑在这宝刀上
I tighten it on this precious blade...
再把刀飞到对面去
and fling it there.
这样我们不是可以攀过去了吗？
So we may climb on it to reach there.
这七彩天蚕丝
Was this wire the ancient treasure...
是不是上一次华山大会
used by Master Tianyi
天一真人用过的上古宝物？
at the last Huashan Meeting?
你怎么知道？
How could you know?
我还知道现在这条天蚕丝
I also know that this wire belongs to...
是在当今皇上第一侍卫的手里
the top royal guard now.
看起来你不是勾子长
I presume you're not Gao Zicheng,
你是朝廷里的第一高手欧展长
but the top royal guard ou Zhancheng.
你为什么知道的那么清楚？
How can you know all details?
因为我这次收钱要杀的人
Because I was paid to kill a royal...
就是身上有一条天蚕丝的御前侍卫
guard who carries the Magic Wire.
你真的是一个为了钱
Are you really a man...
什么都肯做的人？
who will do anything for money?
我从前是，我今后也是
I was and I will be.
也许不是今天
Maybe not today.
但是你要记住，我始终要杀你的
But don't forget; I'll kill you anytime.
可以了吗？
Okay?
可以了
Okay
这绳子真的那么坚韧？
Is this strong enough?
坚韧是够的
Yes, but I'm afraid...
我只怕上面那把刀，插得不够利
the blade didn't stick deep enough.
香师，如果我不幸掉下去
Master Hsiang, if I fall,
你再想办法
you think of another way.
欧大侠，让我先来
Mr. Ou, let me go first.
不，绳子是我的
No, the wire is mine.
现在你们可以上来了
Now you guys may come up here.
李兄，大嫂，请
Mr. Li and Mrs. Li, please...
无名
Wumin...
金小姐，请
Miss Jin, please...
不，我怕
No, I'm scared.
这根绳子这么细
The wire is so thin...
一个背一个，很难平衡
one on another. Very hard to keep balance
让我来帮你们
Let me help you.
大嫂，看看外面有没有人？
Mrs. Li, please look if someone is outside.
拉紧我，把手给他
Hold tight and give him your hand.
一点红，把她接住
Yi Tien-hung. Get her.
我知道了
Got it.
小心，不要怕
Be careful. No need to fear.
小心一点，不要怕，慢慢走过去
Be careful. Take it slowly.
也许不是今天
Maybe not today.
但是你要记住，我始终是要杀你
But don't forget. I'll kill you anytime.
好了，我们全过来了
Okay. We're all over here.
你快点把天蚕丝收回来
You take the wire back now.
我们出去吧
Let's go outside.
快说，犯人囚在哪里？
Tell me. Where are the prisoners?
这就是死囚室？
This is the prison?
是
Yes.
走
Go.
怎么一个人也没有？
Why is no one here?
会不会那守卫骗了我们？
Did the guard lie to us?
不，我从小听爹说过
No. My dad usually constructs...
他盖房子多依八卦两仪
according to Eight Diagrams
生死宿灸的阵法
...and constellation.
如果我估计不错
If I'm not wrong,
这里面还有机关
there'll be a trap inside.
这是生门
This is the door of life
爹？爹？你在哪儿？
Dad? Where are you?
灵芝
Linzhi...
爹
Dad...
报告董王爷
Lord...
死囚室里好像发生了事情
something happened in the prison.
那安全闸关好了没有？
Is the safety gate on?
全部自动关好了
It's on already.
那就没问题了
It's all right then
等拍卖完了之后再去收拾他们
Let's finish them after the auction.
是
Yes.
快...
Hurry up.
大家不要跑...前面很危险
Don't run... It's dangerous ahead.
下面是万丈深渊
It's an abyss.
不要乱跑
Don't run in disorder
怎么样才可以出去啊
How can we get out of here?
你们看，那边那个山洞
It's a cave there.
就是唯一的出路
It's the only exit.
从洞口可以到海边
It leads to the seaside.
你们自己逃生吧
You get out of here yourself.
慢慢走，小心不要掉下去
Walk slowly. Don't fall.
孩子，我们也走吧
Kid, let's go.
慢着，老前辈
Hold it, sir.
请你告诉我到蝙蝠大殿
Please show me the way to...
应该走哪一条路？
the Bat Hall.
你为什么要到蝙蝠大殿
Why are you going there?
因为我要抓蝙蝠公子
Because I need to catch Mr. Bat.
我也答应过一位救命恩人
I've also promised my friend that I need...
给他买药去
to buy medicine for him.
我这一生从来没有被人抓过
I've never been caught by anyone.
我想看一看抓我的是什么人
I'm curious as to who'd want to catch me.
那你们呢？
And you?
我们雍翠山庄有一个规矩
It is a rule of Jade villa.
只要他们是朋友
If our friends are...
当朋友有危险的时候
in danger,
我们跟着一块儿去
we can't leave them alone.
那条路好危险啊
The road is dangerous.
为什么？
Why?
因为我起这蝙蝠岛的时候
When I built this Bat Road,
整个岛我都看过
I had looked through the place.
这几个山洞最危险
These caves are dangerous.
不是万丈深渊就是黑油遍布
Either abysses or black oil grounds
你们看那些火
Look at the fire.
就是黑油冒出来自己烧着的
It's burnt from the black oil.
要到蝙蝠大殿
You've to pass through these...
一定要经过这几个死洞
dead caves to the Bat Hall.
说不定...
Maybe...
我们全都死光了
all of us will die and
也到不了蝙蝠大殿
can't make to the Hall.
这样吧，你告诉我路怎么走
Tell me the way.
我自己一个人去
I'll go there alone.
不，让我们一块儿去
No. Let's go together.
好吧，反正我这条老命
You've saved my life.
也是你们给我捡回来的，跟我来
I'm going too.
跟我来
Come with me.
想不到终于烧起来了
I never expected it to burn to the end
这是什么东西啊
What is it?
这里黑油遍布，而这个山洞特别多
The Black oils are all over the place,
火就是这个黑油烧起来的
especially in this cave.
这火什么时候才会熄啊
When will this fire be put out?
黑油不断流出来
The Black oil comes out endlessly.
永远也不会熄
It'll never be put out.
有没有别的路可以走？
Another way to go?
没有，这几个山洞都是我设计的
No. I designed these caves.
你们看见那个红色的石头没有？
Do you see the red rock?
那是我塞上去的
I put it there.
要至蝙蝠大殿只有这条路
This is the only way to Bat Hall.
把红色的石头抓出来，爬过去
Take the red rock out and climb over.
那么宽的火怎么能跳过去呢？
How can we pass through the broad fire?
而且山洞两边
On both sides of the cave,
也没有可以站的地方啊
there's no space to step on.
能站也没有用啊
It's no use even if you can step on it.
那么大的火一直在烧
The fire burns so fiercely...
石头一定很烫
The rock must be hot like hell.
老前辈我一定要过去
Sir, I must go over there.
要过去只有一个办法
There's only one way.
就是找一个人下去
Someone goes down and blocks the...
把流黑油的洞口堵上
Black oil from the hole.
可是这个人
But the one...
蝙蝠公子是武林大害
Mr. Bat is the bane of the boxers' world
这些孽是我作的
I created these wrong things.
本来应该由我去
It should have been me to go down.
可是我死了
But if I died,
下面的路就没有人带了
no one could show you the way.
灵芝没有武功
Linzhi doesn't know martial art.
就是烧死了也不可能找到洞口
She's not able to find the hole.
所以这件事只有委屈你了
So it'd be wrong of me to ask you to go.
不，老前辈
No, sir
这件事应该由我来做
Let me do it
不用了，我是他养大的
No need. He brought me up.
这是我们金家的事
This is my Jin family's business.
让我来做
Let me do it.
哑巴
Mute buddy
虽然这样没有用，但愿上天保佑你
God bless you.
你叫什么名字？告诉我
What's your name? I'll tell the King...
让我回去禀告皇上，给你封号
who will give you credit.
洞口就在那红色石头的下面
The cave is right under the red rock.
哑巴大哥...            灵芝
- Brother Mute... - Linzhi...
想不到走到这里又是绝路
I never thought it'd again be a dead-end
为什么？
Why?
你们看见那两条横出来的冰柱没有
Do you see the 2 ice pillars there?
三年前，我本来就预备在那里
3 years ago, I tried to blow a hole...
炸一个洞逃走
to escape from here.
可是就在我想炸的那一天
The day when I was going to blow it,
就给他们抓去了
they caught me.
后来我以为
Later I thought
其他的犯人把它给炸通了
other prisoners had blown it.
想不到他们也没有炸
I never imagined they wouldn't have done it
老前辈
sir...
那我们又没有办法到蝙蝠大殿去啦
We got no way to the Hall.
这个洞没有炸开，我们只有回去了
We've to make our way back.
老前辈，你以前准备的炸药呢？
Where's the dynamite you placed?
还好...炸药还在...
Good... it's still there.
药引子没了
The fuse is gone though
我们可以把衣服撕下来做药引啊
We could use our clothes.
这里全是冰雪，寒气极重
The icy air here is humid.
药引也要特制，普通布料绝对不成
Ordinary clothes can't make it.
那怎么办？
What can I do?
只有一个办法，用人去点
Only one way. Using a person as the lead.
而且要两个人
And we need two
因为我早就计算好
I've figured it out.
这个山洞的力点有两个
There're two strength points in this cave
你们看
Look...
就在那两条伸出来的冰柱下面
Right under the two ice pillars.
而且，只有两包炸药同时的爆炸
To blow off the cave, the 2 dynamites...
才能把山洞炸开
must set off at the same time.
但是炸药一爆，那两个人
But when it sets off, these two people...
楚香师，你们看有什么方法
Master Hsiang, can you get my daughter...
能把我们父女送到冰柱上面
and me to the ice pillars?
第一，上那冰柱非有武功不可
First, you've to be well versed in martial arts
第二，要到蝙蝠大殿
second, to go to the Bat Hall...
是我们五个人的事
is what all five of us intend to do.
与你父女无关
Nothing to you two.
这里有五节树枝，两长三短
5 sticks here. 2 short and 3 long.
谁抽到长的谁去点火
One who picks the long one will light fire.
让我来
Me first.
你是短的我是长的
Mine is short and yours is long.
你也是短的，为什么？
Yours is short too. Why?
因为我是御前第一侍卫
Because I'm a royal guard.
除暴安良是我的职责
To fight crimes is my duty.
所以这两个人里面应该有一个是我
I must be one of them.
不过在我死了之后
But after I've died,
希望你们能替我做一件事
please do a favour for me.
就是将这个天蚕丝
Use this silk Wire to...
绑着蝙蝠公子带回去给皇上
tie Mr. Bat up for the King.
为什么是我？
Why me?
你知道我做什么都要钱的
You know I'll do it only for money
就是因为你要钱，所以才交给你
That's why. I want to let you know...
让你知道天下间的事
apart from money, you've got to do...
除了为钱，另外还有应该要做的事
things for other reasons as well
这是我一生里面最后一个要求
This is the last request of my life.
天下的事真奇怪
This world is so strange!
我来这里本来是要杀你的
I came here because I was to kill you.
世事就是这样
That's life.
人与人之间的感情
The feelings between people change...
就随着环境而变化
in accordance with different situations
不过你要答应我
But you've to promise me
用天蚕丝绑着蝙蝠公子
use the silk Wire to tie Mr. Bat up.
那另外一位是谁？
Who's the other one?
玉函，你不能死
Yuhan, you must stay alive.
我们不要到大殿去
We're not going to the Hall.
我们回去...
Let's head back.
无名
Wumin...
刚才我们不是说过吗
Just now we said that...
我们雍翠山庄的人
the people of Jade villa will stay
永远跟朋友在一起
with friends forever.
但是你是李家三代单传
But you're the only son for 3 generations
你不能就这样死在这里
You can't die here.
这只能怪我们李家福薄
If so, it's destined...
注定绝后
that my family will be ended here.
你们不要过来
Don't come over.
这是我们雍翠山庄的事
This concerns Jade villa.
无名，你为什么点了我手脚的穴道
Why do you hit my points?
玉函，当你知道我患了绝症的时候
Yuhan, when I was seriously sick,
你不是说过无论我做什么
did you say you'll agree with...
你都答应我的
whatever I do?
是啊
Yes.
我现在要替你去点火
I'll light the fire for you.
老前辈
Sir...
等我们把洞穴炸开之后
When we blow off the cave,
你在他们背后脊椎骨上
You hit them at the 5th joint of...
第五节重重的敲几下
their backbones
他们的麻穴就会解开
and they'll be able to move again.
老朽知了
I know
大嫂，你还有话要跟大哥说吗？
Mrs. Li, do you have any words for your spouse?
没有了
No
大嫂，请
Mrs. Li, please...
欧大侠请
Mr. Ou, please...
为国除奸，为民除害全靠几位了
The people will appreciate your sacrifice
我去了
I'm going
跟我来
Follow me.
李兄
Mr. Li...
下面轮到星湖大师的手
The hand of Master Xinghu is the next.
及八省巡府的头
The head of the governor of 8 provinces
和五虎门的武功秘笈
The secret book of 5 Tigers school.
准备好了没有？
Ready?
准备好了
Ready
这是楚留香他们的武器
The weapons of Chu and his friends here.
听说死囚室出了事啦
Something's wrong at the prison.
你们要小心一点
You better be careful.
你们出大殿门的时候
While leaving the gate,
记得把手提灯吹熄
remember to dispose it off
知道
sure
我们马上换他们的衣服
We change their clothes immediately...
到大殿去
and go to the Hall.
星湖大师的手，八省巡按的人头
Xinghu's hand and governor's head
五虎门的武功秘笈
The secret book of 5 Tigers school.
要买这些东西的人请准备黄金
Prepare your money for these items
天字号
Tian Zhi Hou.
你们是谁？
Who are you?
雍翠山庄的李玉函
Li Yuhan of Jade villa...
中原一点红
Yi Tien-hung
盗师楚留香
I'm Chu Liu-hsiang.
我们是冲着蝙蝠公子来的
We're here just to take on Mr. Bat
不关事的请离开这儿
Please leave the hall.
你们怎么会逃得出来的？
How could you escape from there?
这只因为蝙蝠岛的气数已尽
As your luck is gone.
住手
Hold it.
凭你们也配
You're too weak...
与江湖上的三位英雄交手
to fight with these 3 heroes
还有两间房的贵宾没走
and the guests in the 2 rooms.
不知道是哪一路英雄
May I ask who you are?
枯梅大师
Master Fumei.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是无花的胞弟
Brother of Wuhua,
东瀛来的无根和尚
Monk Wugan from Japan
去年买你人头的就是我
I tried to buy your head last year.
楚留香果然名不虚传，后会有期
Hsiang's reputation isn't a bluff. Bye.
现在该轮到我办一点家事了
Let me take care of my family matter.
枯梅大师
Master Fumei, didn't...
你不是在船上已经死了吗？
Did you die on the boat?
没有，我只不过发现了
No. I just discovered someone...
有人想买凶手杀我
hiring a killer to get rid of me.
所以我就先装死
So I pretended to be dead first.
随云，你知道谁要杀我吗？
Suiyun, do you know who was after my life?
随云
Suiyun
你怎么晓得是我？
How did you know it's me?
我怎么不晓得
Of course
因为我是你娘，你是我儿子
Because I'm your mom and you're my son.
什么？
What?
二十年前我带着你哥哥
20 years ago, I left your father...
离开你爹
with your elder brother.
后来把你哥哥交给东山二老抚养
I asked Mr. And Mrs. Shandong to...
归隐华山
bring him up and I rested secretly in Huashan.
以为从此以后可以远离尘世
I thought I could avoid the trouble.
谁知道二十年后
But 20 years later, I heard of the...
听说蝙蝠岛危害江湖
Bat Island jeopardizing the boxers' world
而且得你哥哥来信说
Your brother sent me a letter...
蝙蝠公子可能是你
telling me that Mr. Bat could be you.
我叫你哥哥先召集一班江湖义士
I asked him to gather righteous boxers
在四明山庄共商对策却遭人暗算
at simin villa, but they're all killed.
把你哥哥脑部震成白痴
Your brother became mentally retarded
我亲自下山也在你船上遭人刺杀
I was almost killed when showing up again
随云，这些事是不是你干的？
suiyun, didn't you do all of this?
妈，你怎么可以这样说呢？
Mom, how can you say such a thing?
我是你的儿子
I'm your son. How could...
我怎么可以杀你跟哥哥
I try to kill you and my brother?
妈您没事吧？
Are you alright, mom?
没事
I'm alright.
把这个畜牲交给我
Hand over this rascal to me.
畜牲，你还有什么话说？
Well, what do you have to say?
你不但侮辱了无争山庄
You humiliated the Wuchang villa...
你还侮辱了V家的姓氏
and the Yuan's family.
哥哥，你听我说，哥哥我是
Brother, listen to me. I...
住口，去跟妈说去
shut up. Go talk to mom.
别动，为什么？
Stop. Why?
为什么你们做母亲的
Why did you and him have to...
做哥哥的一定要管我
meddle in my affairs?
其实我跟你们已经分开了二十年
I was separated from you for 20 years.
母亲从来没养过我
You didn't raise me.
我也不认识你
Even I didn't know you
你们一定很希望知道
You must be really eager to know...
我为什么要做蝙蝠公子
why I became the Mr. Bat.
就是因为我的家声太好
Coz my family's reputation is too good.
就算我的武功再高，本领再大
No matter how good I'm in martial art,
也只不过是一个无争山庄的传人
I'm the only heir to Wuchang villa;
我父亲的儿子
the only son of my father.
有谁知道
Who ever knows...
我是集天下武功于一身的V随云
I'm the most powerful Yuan suiyun
只有这样
only by doing things
做一点跟你们完全相反的事
completely different from you guys
你们才会留意到
can catch your attention that
天下间有一个武功比你们高的瞎子
there's a blind man better than you.
只有这样
Only by doing so,
才能把上天对我的不公平
I can avenge...
来一点报复
the unfairness of my destiny.
哪一点上天对你不公平？
What's unfair to you?
为什么我是私生子？
Why was I an abandoned son?
为什么你们看得见我看不见？
Why was I blind?
你是谁？
Who are you?
用手抓着我的剑不要命吧？
How dare you grab my sword?
要命就不是一点红
If I don't dare, I'm not Yi Tien-hung
孩子们，把火灭了退出去
Children, put out the fire and leave.
快下机关
Start the traps.
你们有没有听说过一句话
Have you heard that...
在没有光的地方
in a dark place,
瞎子的武功是最高的
the blind is the most powerful.
因为你们看不到我出手
It's because you can't see how I attack,
而我却能听得到你们在哪里
but I can hear where you are.
你们现在什么东西都看不见了吧
You don't see a single thing now.
不过还有一样东西你们找得到的
But there's a thing you can see.
就是黄泉路，鬼门关
That's the road to hell!
V公子
Mr. Yuan...
现在你们大概后悔
Now you may regret
为什么要多管闲事了吧
that you're too officious.
好了，我不再给你们开玩笑了
Okay. No more kidding.
从现在开始
From now on,
我一个一个的把你们杀掉
I'll kill all of you one by one.
让我想想第一个先杀谁
Let me see which one would I start with...!
还是先杀多管闲事的楚留香吧
Kill the officious Chu Liu-hsiang first.
蝙蝠公子
Mr. Bat.
你为什么不第一个先杀我
Why don't you kill me first?
是不是怕我一点红？
Aren't you scared of me, Yi Tien-hung?
什么？我怕你一点红？
What? I afraid of you?
好吧，那我就不先杀楚留香
Okay. Lemme spare Hsiang for a while.
先杀你一点红
I'll kill Yi Tien-hung first.
你们这几招倒很厉害啊
These attacks are really lethal.
怎么样？一点红死了没有？
What? Is Yi Tien-hung dead?
我怎么会死呢？
How would I die?
我只不过伤了一条手臂
I was just hurt in the arm.
我一点红要杀你蝙蝠公子
I'm going to kill you, Mr. Bat.
只有一只手臂就够了
One arm will be enough.
真的吗？可惜你们不知道我在哪里
Really? But you don't know where I am
就算武功再高也没有用
No matter how good you fight...
你们等着死吧
You are going to die.
怎么样？看不到我很难出手吧
It's hard to attack without seeing him.
我教你们，下次跟我交手
Next time when you deal with me,
带多一点火蜡
bring more candles.
可惜你们再也没有这个机会了
But you wouldn't get a second chance, would you!
奇怪？他们怎么看得到我的出手呢
How can they see my hands?
他们是不是听到
Do they hear...
我身上珍珠的声音？
the sound of pearl on my body?
原来武林里面传说的无价之宝
So you've the most priceless treasure
南海明珠果然在你们手上
the Pearl of south sea.
可惜只得一颗
It's a pity that you've only one pearl.
你们再没有第二颗了
You don't have another one.
还有，从现在开始
From now on,
你们的下一战就是鬼门关
the next battle will take you to hell.
李兄...
Mr. Li
楚香师
Master Hsiang...
如果你有机会
If you get a chance,
请把我的尸体带回冰窟里
take my dead body back to the ice cave
好让我跟无名永远在一起
so that I can stay with Wumin forever.
这一招就是黑魔教的绝艺
The most lethal attack of Black Devil school
以其人之剑还杀其人
to kill you with your own sword.
跟着我就会把你们的武器夺下
I'll take your weapons...
杀死你们
and kill you with them.
V公子
Mr. Yuan...
随风，你怎么样了？
suiyun, how are you?
现在剩下的只有楚留香了
Hsiang is the only one left now.
随云...
Suiyun...
他这是干嘛？
What's he doing?
他曾经答应过一个死去的朋友
He promised a deceased friend that,
无论怎么样
come what may;
都要把蝙蝠公子的尸体绑回去
he will tie Mr. Bat's body up...
交给皇上
to hand over to the King.